Friends, whenever we purchase insurance for our bike or
scooter from anywhere,
we directly suffer a
loss of 20 to 25%.
Because those people deduct some commission or the other.
But in today's video, whatever
I am going to tell you,
you can save 20 to 25% of your money
because I am going to tell you the direct method.
But friends, whenever we take
insurance, we always have to keep two things in
mind that first of all, from
where should we take insurance and
which type of insurance should we take.  Look, first of all let
me tell you
which insurance you have to take.
For example, let's assume that brother, I have a
Splendor bike.
And do you know that a
total of three types of insurance can be sold for this Splendor bike also.  First of all,
our first
party insurance comes.  Second comes
comprehensive insurance or what
we also call zero dep.  And third comes to
us third party insurance.
Many people here
prefer to purchase third party insurance.  Let
me
first clear some things to you about all three insurances.
Listen to this carefully so that
you do not face any problem in purchasing insurance.  First of all, let
us talk about
third party insurance here.
So friend, look, we have third party
insurance here.  Now see
why do we get insurance?  First of all, if we assume that
our bike or scooter gets
damaged somewhere.  Somewhere an accident or something happens.
So
we purchase insurance to cover the claim of that accident
or to
avoid challan from the police.  So look, our
third party plan will
save you from the police.  But third
party insurance will not cover any
accident involving your vehicle if it happens by any chance.
But this insurance of ours
covers the vehicle of the person in front of us.  For example, let us
assume that I was taking my Splendor
on the road and by any chance,
due to any reason, if my Splendor
collides with someone else's bike, then
my bike will definitely get damaged.
But only the bike in front will get
damaged.  So what does the company do in this case
?  That is, look at the third party
insurance,
this insurance can provide the claim to the other person.
But it does
not provide you the claim.  This would have been
our third party insurance.
But if you had purchased first party
insurance,
what would have happened in the first party case?  This will
also save you from the police.  Plus, it also covers any accidental damages that occur to your vehicle.
For example, if my car collides, then the
person in front will definitely get cover.
Plus, if I
want to claim for my vehicle, I will be able to
claim for any accidental damage to my vehicle.
And if you
take a comprehensive plan or a zero depth plan here, then all the
wear and tear
parts are also
covered under this insurance.
For example, if you have any nuts, bolts,
etc., or any wear and tear
parts, if you want, then the more you tick,
the more your premium will
increase.  Look, normally the people who take it,
either they take your first party or
they take the third party plan.  If
I tell you in simple words, then brother,
if you do not have a car then many people
prefer to take the first party plan.
If the car is 5-6 years old,
then many people
prefer to take a third party plan.
Now, let me tell you in a few minutes
how you
can purchase your car insurance while sitting at home
and see, the website which I am going to tell you, first of all,
its claim ratio is very strong and all
your work gets
completed online.  The process that I am going to
tell you, brother,
take out 5 to 10 minutes of time and watch it properly once.
Everything will become absolutely
clear to you.  Then let's
start the program.  So friends, here you
can see that the
website I am going to tell you about for purchasing insurance
is apo.com.  If you want its direct
link, I will put it in the description box below.
Now here you can see that
your insurance starts at a very low rate.  Let
me quickly
tell you what you have to do to get insurance.  First of all
you have to
enter the number of your bike or scooter
whichever is on your number plate.  After that
you have to click on Simply View Prices.
Now here you will have to get your brand or
model verified.  As you
can see, first of all you have to
select the brand and model here.  As
you can see here, we will have many
models.  You can see as per your convenience
which bike you have.
After that, the registration number of when you got the bike
registered will be
inside your RC.  You have to
basically select that year here.
After that you have to proceed.  After that friends,
he is asking
what is the status of your current policy?  The
first option we see is Not Expired.   That
means it has not expired yet.   The
policy is still lying in our current account.
Now it means that it is going to expire in two-three days.  something like that.
After that it says
expired in the last 90 days.   That
means your policy will expire in 90 days.
And the third one is saying
that the expiry is more than 90 days.  That means it has been
more than 90 days since your
policy expired.  Look brother, if there are
too many then you will have to get
verification done here etc.  This means that
you will have to take a photo etc. and upload it.
And you will have to follow the same process even if your
policy expires within 90 days.
If your policy has
not expired then you do
not need to do anything.  You can also
see a new policy for the same policy.  But
if your policy has expired then
you will have to provide proof here because
friend, let's assume that my
policy has expired.  There was some damage to my car
and they made a policy and
I should go and claim it tomorrow.  So brother, things don't
work like that.  First they will see whether
your car is completely safe or
not.  Only then will they allow you to
buy insurance.  If my car
is completely safe.  I will make a photo video and
send it to them.  After that my policy will be
implemented.  And if there is any damage from anywhere,
they will write a damage report saying that this was
already damaged.  If you claim it later, it will
not be given to you.
And brother, this happens everywhere.  Now here
you can see that my car has arrived here.
I am going to tell you the IDB value now.
And brother, this is a very important thing.
Listen to this carefully.
After that we are being asked
to select the tenure here.  1 year, 2
years or 3 years.  For how many years do you
want to take the policy?  But before the policy, let me
tell you the IDB value once.
IDB value is our
insured value.  That is,
what will be the total value of our car?
For example, you can see that our ₹61,100 will be
our highest ID value
and ₹32,900 will be our lowest
ID value and our IDV value is
currently around 47,000, that is, in the middle.
Look, the meaning of IDV value is that
for example, if my car catches
fire, gets stolen, or gets totaled, then in
that case, the company
from which I am purchasing the insurance will pay
me only the IDV value.
And if you increase or decrease the IDV value, then the
amount in your insurance premium will also increase or decrease very slightly.
So brother,
I would say that you should keep your IDB
value very high so that even
if there is a total loss
or if due to any reason your vehicle gets
totally lost, then at least you will get
coverage of a higher amount.
That's why friends, I also
always keep my IDB value high.
After that I click on continue.
Now here I have to select for
how many years I want to take the policy.
Here you will see that you have a third
party plan and a comprehensive
plan.  I have already made it clear to you.
So now you will
not need to use much brain here.  The third party plan that is being given to us here is
for ₹714 and our
comprehensive plan is only for ₹13.  This
is the only difference between the two plans.  At the same time,
if I select a 2 year plan, then the
comprehensive
plan becomes ₹1949 and our third
party plan becomes ₹1428
and similarly, your 3 year plan will be
₹2843 comprehensive and
our third party plan will be ₹2142.
So brother, you should see as per your convenience as to
how many years' plan you want to purchase.
Now friends, if you finally see here,
I have selected my plan for one year.
I will not take this comprehensive plan right now.  Right now I would
like to take a third party plan here because
my bike etc. remains lying empty in the house.
I just take it out sometimes.
So for that I just have to make a purchase.
And when the bike doesn't work that well,
why should I invest money in the first party here
?  But if your bike or scooter will be used for
daily running then you should
take a comprehensive plan here.
I would prefer this to you.  Now let me
tell you what all
we get to see in the comprehensive plan.
For example, in case of an accident, if
your vehicle is totally lost or
damaged, then here you will be covered for the
repair cost or replacement cost if your
bike is damaged due to an accident or if it is
damaged due to fire, then
you will be covered in that case also.  If there is
theft, then
you will be covered in that case also.
But make sure that you have both your keys with you in case of theft.
After that, climate means if there is a
flood anywhere, an earthquake etc.
, something falls on your bike or scooter, then
you will get a claim in that case.
Third party injury or
death occurs.  That means, the third party, the
person in front of us, whom we hit or if
anything happens, then a claim is provided to him also by a company
and the
property of the third party also, that is, the bike etc. of the
person in front with whom our bike
etc. has hit, will
also be provided a claim.  So
friends, these were the benefits of our comprehensive plan.
And I will also tell you when these benefits will not be given to you.
Non-accidental damage means if your
tyre, tube, engine etc. gets
damaged, then in this case you are
not given cover for the damage etc.  And if you
drive illegally, that is, if you
break the traffic law or
you drive without a driving license
or if you drive after consuming alcohol or drunk
etc., then in that case
you will not be given any claim here.
You have to keep this in mind.
After that, let me tell you the benefits of third party
plans also.   For example, in case of
third party injury or
death,
coverage will be provided to him in that case also
and coverage is also provided to the property of the third party.
And what these people do not cover under the third party
plan is own bike damage, that is, if
our own bike gets damaged then
we will not get any coverage at all
and if you do illegal driving
then you will not get any coverage in that also.
So friends,
I am going to select my third party plan here.
So I select it and
click on continue.
After that, you will see here that we are being given
personal accidental cover.
If you already have it, you
can skip it if you want.  Otherwise, you also get
personal accidental cover of ₹15 lakh sum assured for ₹350.   If
you want, you can also add it on.  It's
totally up to you.  This is basically optional.
Now here you will see that you will have to enter some of your
personal details.  Like
you have to give your full name here.  Give your email
ID, mobile number, pin
code and if you have GST then this is
optional.  If you want to give it, you can give it, otherwise
you can also skip it.  Now here
you can see that
whatever details of the bike etc. we had entered in the review and details,
all the things have reached us.  You
must check out your ID value carefully here once.  And
you must also verify here which plan you are taking.
So let me
quickly process this payment.  Now
friends, here you can see that I am being asked to do it for
₹843.
I quickly
complete my payment here through PhonePe or Google Pay.
Now friends,
after completing the payment etc., you will
also have to get your complete KYC done here.  Look,
any person who has a bike or scooter has to
submit his PAN card and Aadhar card here.  And make sure that the
payment should also be made from his account.
And friends, this rule has been
implemented in all the companies.  Whether you take
your policy online or offline.  And the
rule has come into effect from July 1, 2023.  So
let us quickly
complete our KYC.  Now
friends, to get KYC done here,
you simply have to get your PAN card number verified.
After that, if
you want, you can also give your Aadhar card etc. as address proof.
We will
complete all the work here through DJkar only.  You can see that first of all
you have to enter your full name.
Government ID on S.  After that you have to
accept their terms and conditions and
click on the continue button.
After continuing, here
you have to enter your PAN card number according to the government ID
and here you
also have to enter your date of birth.
I complete both the things quickly.  After that
I will click on the proceed button.
Now here two options are being given for your document verification.  If
you want, you
can get it done manually or you
can also get your document verified through Digilocker.
Friends, we are going to give our driving license here.  You
can see that
after selecting the driving license, now you have to
upload the driving license from your front side as well as from the back side.
Here I simply enable permissions for camera etc.
After that I upload my driving license from the front side.
You
can see here that it has been uploaded.  I will simply
click on Use This Photo.  After that you
can see that almost all our work is complete.
Here you basically have to enter your city.
Gender has to be selected.
Male, female, whatever.  After that you will
also have to choose a relation here.  Let's assume
brother that whatever company is there in any case.
Look, this is a hypothetical case
that if something serious happens to you, then
whom should you contact in that case
?  So here I would like to create Father.
First Name of Your Relation and
Last Name of Your Relation.  Now complete both the details
here.  After that you have to
finally click on the submit button.
Now friends, here you can finally see
that our KYC verification has been
successfully completed.  I did
all the work in front of you.  Now
as soon as your KYC is verified, it is done immediately,
which means
after the payment is complete, your KYC is verified
and after that our policy is issued to us
and see, it takes two to three
minutes for your policy to be issued.
Here you can
see your policy in PDF format.  As
you can see here, our bike
etc. is being shown.
You will also be able to see the dates when your policy is starting and when it is ending.  I will
blur this out for security reasons.
And here you are
given the option to download the policy.  Rest friend,
if you take your policy as a by any chance and
someday there is some damage etc.
and you want to claim for it, then to
claim it you will have to
talk to their customer care number and
whatever your claim is, an
attempt is made to settle it quickly here.
That's why I am recommending you to buy Ekko here
because brother it is a very
best application.  I myself get my
policies etc. done through this website.
So friends, this was the
complete process of getting your bike or scooter
insured.  Once you
comment, please tell me which bike you have
and for how much you are purchasing its policy.
Rest of the friends, we will meet in
our next video, till then
Jai Hind Jai